下一位
[Clerk 1] Next, pIease.
快点…
Come on, come on.
下一位
CLERK 2: Next.
名字
Name.
格斯高曼
Gus Gorman.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
（请这里稍候）
有了 格斯高曼
Ah, yes. August Gorman.
你希望这星期说上班吗?
Have you Iooked for work this week?
- 是的  - 想做什么?
- Yes. - What kind?
- 厨房技师 - 洗盘子 找到了吗?
- Kitchen technician. - Dishwasher. Any Iuck?
不 但是…
No, but...
高曼先生 根据资料显示 你已经36个星期没工作了
Mr. Gorman, according to our records, you've been unempIoyed for 36 weeks.
不对 只有35个星期
No, it's 35.
这星期不算
Not counting this week.
你上一份工作 是在保全公司送信
You secured empIoyment in June as a messenger and were discharged after...
- 只做一天就… - 不是 他们说我把信搞丢了
- ...one day for Iosing... - No, they said I ost it.
但我根本没有弄丢 是被别人偷走的
I did not ose it! It was stoIen by a pickpocket.
一部电视机?
A teIevis on set?
是一部日本超小型 迷你电视机
It was a teeny- tiny, teeny- weensy Japanese te evision set.
然后你又在一家速食店工作 只做了…
The other empIoyment you found was in a fast- food joint, which Iasted...
28分钟
...28 minutes?
你的记录居然都是这样 真是快
That's some kind of record. TaIk about fast.
你知道那些人都是疯子 要你在一天内学会所有的事情
Those peop e are crazy. They expect you to Iearn that stuff in one day.
要拿生菜 拿蕃茄酱 然后又要酱汁
''Ho d the Iettuce. HoId the ketchup. Can I have some sauce, p ease?"
- 高曼先生… - 要面包 不要面包 又要起司
- Mr. Gorman... - "Two buns. No buns. Some cheese."
高曼先生 大都会市对无业游民 是非常仁慈 但是…
Mr. Gorman, the c ty of MetropoIis is generous to a fauIt, but...
我不是无业游民
I'm not the fauIt!
在失业了36个星期之后
Thirty- six weeks of chronic unempIoyment.
没有尽到缴税的义务 36个星期了
Thirty- s x weeks of Iiv ng off the taxes of hard- work ng citizens.
- 你知道你自己目前的处境吗? - 别说我是无业游民 我不是
- Do you know what you are? - Don't caII me a bum, I'm not a bum!
你是 而我要说的是 你无法再申请了
You are, I was about to say, no Ionger e igibIe.
- 听着… - 下一位
- WeII, Iook... - Next.
那这个星期该怎么办? 我这星期还要过活
Wait. What about this week? I need this week!
下一位
Next.
你是认真的吗?
You mean, that's it?
确定不能了?
"F nished," Iike "over"?
[PHONE RINGS]
下一位
CLERK 2: Next.
下一位就表示再见
GUS: "Next" as in " bye."
下一位
CLERK 2: Next!
名字
Name.
对不起 兄弟 可以借个火吗?
Excuse me, brother, can I have a Iight?
（赚大钱  成为电脑程式设计师）
主演：克里斯多夫李维
- 你好 艾里 - 嗨 吉米
- How you doing, AIex? VENDOR: Hi, Jimmy.
主演：理查普莱尔
[SKATER YELLS]
[PEOPLE YELL]
[DOG BARKS]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
片名：超人3
[PENGUIN CHRPS]
[DOGS BARK]
[GLASS BREAKS]
主演：贾基库伯
Huh? Ah.
[PENGUIN CHRPS]
主演：马克麦克劳
[PAPER TEARS]
主演：安奈特欧突尔
主演：安妮罗斯
[MAN GRUNTS]
主演：帕美拉史蒂芬森
对不起
Excuse me.
[GUNFIRE AS PEOPLE SCREAM]
（世纪储蓄银行）
主演：罗勃范 惑
玛歌基德饰演露易丝莲恩
[INDISTINCT CHATTER AND SHOUTING]
要说谢谢
MOTHER: Say thank you.
Wow!
太棒了 超人
Way to go, Superman!
编剧：大卫纽曼 雷斯利纽曼
制片：皮尔史班葛
导演：李察莱斯特
（资讯教室）
你的饮料马上说来了
VOICE [ON MACHINE] Your drlnk is on its way.
老师
WOMAN: Sir.
对不起
Excuse me...
但是 有关于这个程式 二个位元同时混合一起运作
...but what if you wanna program two biIateraI coordinates at the same time?
你不可以这样作 这不可能的
You can't do that. It's impossib e.
- 但如果你不能的话… - 不
WOMAN: But f you can't ... - Oh, no.
电脑技术对年轻小姐是很先进 但你不可这样做
Computer techno ogy s very advanced, young Iady, but it can't do that.
如果你觉得我们不能这样作 那么你觉得是不是可以…
WOMAN: But f you think we can't do it that way, what happens...?
老师
GUS: Sir.
天呀
TEACHER: Good Lord.
你怎么办到的?
How did you do that?
我不知道 我说是办到了
I don't know. I just did it.
（《每日星球报》）
- 他是谁? - 此是他 罗斯维斯伯
PERRY: Who's this? [Jimmy] That's him, Ross Webster.
他刚得到年度人道奖
[Jimmy] Just after he received the award for Humanitarian of the Year.
他很英俊
He is good- Iooking.
因为我用特殊镜头拍的
Because I gave him f.2 at a 50th.
有一件事我不明白
One th ng I don't understand...
专题的重点采访的是 罗斯维斯伯如何获得这个荣誉
...the point of the story Lois wrote is how Ross got this great honor...
而你只拍一张他的照片 却拍了十五张她的照片
...and you br ng me one picture of him and 15 pictures of this other person.
- 她是谁? - 罗蕾莱 她是维斯伯的…
PERRY: Who is she? - LoreIe Ambrosia. She's Webster's ...
她就是跟着维斯伯 我们不要谈个
She's just Webster's . Let's eave it at that.
- 这个女人是谁? - 他的妹妹 佛庄
PERRY: Who's this other woman? [Jimmy] His sister, Vera Webster.
- 照片不清楚 - 什么?
PERRY: P cture Iooks fuzzy. - What?
长官 这看起来很清楚 就好像活生生地站在面前
The picture's fine, chief. She Iooks I ke that in reaI Iife.
- 她是维斯寇集团的副总裁 - 我真的无法明白
- She's VP of Webscoe Industries. - I reaIIy don't understand you.
你去参加个无聊宴会 带回来三千张无聊的照片
A boring banquet and you bring me 3000 boring pictures.
超人今早在第三街 解救快溺死在车里的人
Yet Superman saves a man from drowning on Third Avenue...
而你却傻呼呼地站在旁边 竟连一张照片也没拍
...whiIe you just stand there and you don't bring me one picture!
老板 我当时没有带照相机
Chief, I didn't have my camera with me.
摄影记者吃饭也带着照相机 摄影记者睡觉也带着照相机
A photographer eats with his camera. A photographer sIeeps with his camera.
- 我很庆幸我只是个文字记者 - 怀特先生 请吧
- I'm gIad I'm a writer. - Mr. White, pIease.
需要你抽出本月的幸运号码
It's t me for you to draw this month's winn ng JINGO number.
奖品是免费到南美的旅游机会
Prze is an aII- expenses trip to South America.
- 真是蠢啊 - 早安各位
- I don't know why the idiot in CircuIation... CLARK: Good morning.
- 嗨 克拉克 - 嗨 露易丝 早安吉米
- Hi, CIark. - Hi, Lois. Morning, Jimmy.
你领口有一点芥末
You've got mustard on your apeI.
怀特先生 我不想打扰你
Excuse me, Mr. White, I hate to interrupt...
对不起 我现在很忙 我有篇文章要赶
Sorry. I'm busy. I got a paper to get out here.
一旦交到印刷厂 就不能再更换的
It' never rep ace the printing press.
- 怀特先生 号码是几号? - 五十三号
- What's the number, Mr. White? - Fifty- three.
- 怀特先生… - 五十三号
- Mr. White... SECRETARY: Fifty- three!
- 怀特先生… - 你还要多转出三个号码
CLARK: Mr. White... - You've got to puII three more numbers.
但是我答应要回他们电话 你的意思如何?
I promised I'd caII them back today. What do you think?
- 我不知道 肯特 我个人是… - 我想一定可以写出精彩的故事
- WeII, I don't know, Kent... - I think it'd make a terrific story.
什么样精彩的故事?
What's a terrific story?
- 他被邀请回去参加高中同学会 - 没错
Kent's been invited to his high- schooI reunion.
- 真的 - 是啊
- Say. CLARK: Yeah.
可以再来把号码转出来吗?
CouId we have the next number?
这是美国的习俗嘛 对吧 吉米?
It's practica y an American inst tution. Isn't it?
我不知道 我高中的同学 还在念高中
I don't know, Mr. Kent. Most of the peopIe I know are st I in h gh schooI.
33号
Thirty- three.
我想这个故事 可以写有关…
What I thought this story would be about, Mr. White, is...
33号
SECRETARY: Thirty- three.
在过去15年问 典型的小镇究竟有多大转变
...is how much the typicaI smaII town has changed in the ast 15 years.
拿我作个例子
Take me, for exampIe:
我在接受过大都会的洗礼后 还可以回到美中地区生活吗?
Can I reaIIy go back to m ddIe America now as a MetropoIis sophisticate?
我想到这里就觉得很兴奋 甚至我昨晚…
I'm reaIIy excited about this. In fact, I was Iook ng around...
在我的衣柜里…
...in my cIoset Iast night...
找到我高中时代的运动衣
...and I even found my oId h gh- schooI sweater.
- 小镇 - 怀特先生
- SmaIIviIIe. - Mr. White.
我可以计划到那里去旅游吗?
Can I go ahead and make my traveI pIan?
我也有同样的问题要问你
Same quest on about mine.
告诉你那些同学 大记者要衣锦荣归了
TeII your peopIe the prodigaI son and his photographer are coming home.
谢谢 怀特先生
Oh, gee, thanks, Mr. White.
我要告诉你 对我来说 最好的记者不在身边实在不好
It sn't easy for me to Iose one of my best reporters.
- 没问题的 - 你应该放假 露易丝
- That's okay. - You deserve the vacation, Lois.
谢谢
Thank you.
露易丝 你要去什么地方玩吗?
Lois, are you going somep ace?
克拉克 有人千方百计要去小镇
CIark, you know some peopIe get to go aII the way to Sma viIIe...
但也有些人 向往着要去百慕达
...and then there are others of us who have to go to Bermuda.
天哪
GoIIy.
再见
LOIS: Bye. [Jimmy] Bye, Miss Lane.
- 玩得尽兴 - 怀特先生 你还要抽一个号码
- Have fun. - Mr. Wh te, the next number, pIease.
我想我也该走了
WeII, I guess I better be going too.
那我要走了
So I'II be going.
再见
Bye.
难道不能用电脑来做吗?
CouIdn't we get a computer to do this?
（维斯寇集团 电脑资讯中心）
- 这是什么? - 你的第一份薪水
- Hey, what is this? - First paycheck.
但我一个星期 应该有2 25元吧
This is the first rip- off, man! We're supposed to get 225 a week, rght?
现在只拿到143点8元 这样如何过活?
This says, ''$143.80.'' How am I supposed to l ve on that?
州税 联邦税 社会安全税…
State tax, federaI tax, socia security tax...
等到65岁 你就可以拿到被扣掉的钱了
It's so you're stiII getting some money when you hit 65.
要等到65岁才拿得到钱?
So I'm getting money when I...? 65?
但我现在就需要钱
I want mine now!
我要趁年轻享受 没有钱我怎能享受
I want to enjoy it whiIe I'm young. I wanna get up and get down. Boogie.
事实上应该有 143点8元再加上半毛钱
ActuaIIy, it's probabIy more Iike $143.80 and one ha f cent.
总是会有剩余的钱 但是都是公司拿走了
There are aIways fractions Ieft over, but big corporations round it down.
半毛钱有什么用? 塞牙缝都不够
What do I do with haIf a cent? Buy a thoroughbred mouse?
每个人剩余的钱都被拿走了?
Everybody Ioses those fract ons?
不能说被拿走了 因为你根本没有拿到手上过
They don't Iose them. You can't Iose what you never got.
然后呢? 是公司拿走的吗?
Then what happens? The company gets them?
也不是 他们根本不会像你一样 如此在意此事
They can't be bothered coIIecting that from your paycheck any more than you.
那钱会如何处理?
Then what happens to them?
只有电脑知道资金的运作情况 知道钱在哪里
WeII, they're just f oating around out there. The computers know where.
糖要多少?
How many sugars?
一个半
One and a haIf.
下班了 格斯 你还不走?
It's quitting time, Gus. You coming?
嗯 但我还有些事情 没做完 所以…
Yeah. No, actua Iy, I got some stuff to f nish up, so....
加班工作?想干什么? 想要加薪吗?
Working overtime, huh? What are you doing, buddy? Looking for a raise?
对 想要加薪
Yeah, Iooking for a ra se.
(3 6 8 2 2 X4)
（格斯高曼
3 6 8 2 2 X4)
（维斯寇集团薪资项目 更新安全系统）
（准许进入 更正薪资项目）
（指示更正事项）
（维斯寇集团所有剩余薪资 薪水转入以上的帐户）
好了
GUS: You bet.
我姑父站在支持我父亲的一边 他不吃她烹调的东西
[Jimmy] But my UncIe A on my father's side, he won't eat her stuffing.
他说火鸡该从外面烤 她却要从里面烤
He says it shouId be cooked on the outside. She cooks it on the inside.
我妈说 我姑母海伦是我爸的干妹
My mother toId my Aunt HeIen. She's my father's haIf sister.
- 我告诉过你 对吗? - 对
- I toId you that, right? - Yeah.
- 总之… - 嘿…
- And anyway, the fam Iy... - Hey, hey.
你看 哗
- Look at that. [Jimmy] Wow.
[SIRENS WA L]
你可以选择开回去 或是靠边停 等到结束为止
Okay, your choice: You can turn back or puII over tiII it's over.
- 要等多久呢? - 无法判断
- How Iong wiII it take? - Can't teII w th these fires.
这种火烧起来 会有蔓延的可能
I mean, that fire... That's spreading Iike wiIdfire.
不过只是一栋建筑物着火罢了
DRIVER: It's just a buiIding burning.
一栋建筑物? 这是化学工厂呀
It's not just a buiIding. That's a chemica p ant.
你懂我的意思了吧  化学工厂起火
You know what I mean. It's Iike... It's I ke chemicaIs.
随时可能会有浓烟 将这附近给遮盖住
If any of that stuff goes up n smoke, we're in for a hairy time around here.
放轻松
- 克拉克 - 是
- CIark. - Yeah?
你替我分散他们的注意力 这样他们才不知道我要干嘛
I want you to keep these peopIe distracted.
你要干什么?
What are you doing?
干什么? 你记得老板的话吗?
What am doing? Remember what the ch ef said?
摄影记者永远要配合上报导
A photographer aIways goes after a story.
但这很危险的 吉米
That couId be dangerous, Jimmy.
危险 它是随时存在的 肯特
Danger goes with the terrtory, Mr. Kent.
[FIREMEN SHOUT INDISTINCTLY]
救命
HeIp me!
- 我能帮得上忙吗? - 帮他拿顶头盔
- How can I heIp? - Get this man a heImet.
- 喔 是你 你来得正好 - 情况如何?
- It's you. Forget the heImet. - How bad is it?
天呀 超人 这真像一场恶梦 所有的东西不是爆炸就是冒烟
My God, t's a nightmare. Everything's either expIosive or fIammab e or worse.
[EXPLOSION]
快把云梯车开过来
Get the Iadder truck in here.
- 构不着 - 天呀 他们被困住了
- It won't reach. - My God, they're trapped!
他要干什么? 一次载一个下来吗?
What's he gonna do? F y them down one at a t me?
[WORKERS YELL]
走吧 大家从这里走 快走
Let's go! Everybody, down there! Move it!
来啊 快点
Come on! Hurry up!
好了
There you go.
从这里 慢慢来
Right down there. Take it easy.
好了 所有人都下去
AII rght. Everybody down there!
MAN: Keep moving!
先生 你要离开这里越快越好
Sir, get out. I'lI show you the quickest way.
我要照顾这些仪器 不能离开这里
Go on. Look after the others. I can't Ieave.
- 为何? - 我要照顾那些物品
- Why not? - I gotta stay and Iook after those.
这些是浓缩的硫化酸
That's concentrated BeItric acid.
如果热度超过180度 就会过热燃烧
If that stuff heats up over 180 degrees, we've got a cris s...
所引起的危机及火势 就不可收拾
...that' make this fire Iook Iike a p cn c.
那要怎么办?
SUPERMAN: What does it do?
如果保持温度稳定 就没问题
CHEMIST: As Iong as it rema ns stabIe, it's just ordinary acid.
但一旦开始受热 它就很容易会爆炸
But if it begins to heat up, it' turn voIatiIe.
就会有很浓的烟雾 会穿透任何的东西
You'lI get a great cIoud of smoke that wiII eat through anything.
钢铁 水泥 任何的东西
SteeI, concrete, anything.
[FIREMEN SHOUT INDISTINCTLY]
你在那里搞什么鬼?
Who the heII is that?
- 嘿 离开那里  - 我只是拍几张火灾的照片
FIREMAN: Hey, you! Get off of there! - I'm just gonna get a coupIe more shots.
Ow! Ah!
叫他们快点来灭火 快点
TeI them to bring their hoses back here! QuickIy!
救命
[Jimmy] HeIp!
HeIp! HeIp me!
救命 有人能救我吗
HeIp! Somebody he p me!
- 救命  - 没事了
- HeIp! - It's aII right.
- 超人 我的腿 - 我抓到你了 轻松点
- Superman! My Ieg. - I got you. Take it easy.
我们慢慢来
AII right. We'lI go nice and easy.
喔 抱歉 好了吗?走罗
Okay, 'm sorry. AII right? Here we go.
担架 快过来
Medics! Over here, pIease.
好了 可以了
That's it. Here you go.
轻轻地 他左腿骨折了
Go easy. It's the Ieft Ieg.
- 照相机 - 是
- My camera. - Yeah.
只是单纯的骨折
It's a cIean break right across the fibuIa.
- 我的照相机 - 抱歉 吉米 你会没事的
- My camera. - Sorry, J mmy. You' I be okay.
你们要集中水扑灭实验室的火 不然里面的硫化酸会过热爆炸
Get that f re out, otherwise there'lI be an ac d cIoud a I over the Eastern seaboard.
- 天啊 抽水车没作用了  - 什么?
FIREMAN 1: The pump house is gone! FIREMAN 2: What?
- 抽水车  - 我们抽不到水了
FIREMAN 1: The pump house! - We've Iost the water pressure!
- 我们要找到水来  - 要怎么找?
- We've got to have water! - How?
卡摩嘉湖离这里五英里路 五英里的远水救不了近火
Lake Comooga's five miIes from here. We'd need a five- miIe hose!
- 湖在哪里? - 那边
- Where's this Iake? - That way.
告诉他们没希望了
TeII them it's hopeIess.
是你说水源充足的
You toId me we had an adequate water suppIy.
水来了
Water!
真不敢相信 那人是个奇蹟
I teII you, that man's a miracIe!
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYS IN SCHOOL]
[PEOPLE CHATTER INDISTINCTLY]
（欢迎返校 1965毕业班）
卡罗 你真漂亮
WOMAN: CaroI, you got gorgeous!
（小镇 帽子3元）
看看你
Look at you.
（布莱德威尔逊 64年全州明星球员）
那次对抗城中队 我永生难忘
BRAD: That was against Mid- City. I'lI never forget t.
第四节 打成平手
Fourth quarter, score was t ed...
我们在二十五码线上
...we're back at the 25- yard Iine.
教练下达指令 右翼突破
Coach sends in a pIay, Right FIanker Option.
你真的长大了不少 克拉克
You reaIIy have grown, C ark.
你身体也不错 班尼丝太太
You Iook very weII, M ss Bann ster.
算是不错了 虽然爬楼梯慢点 记忆还不错
I can't compIa n. take the sta rs a ittIe s ow and I have these spe Is.
我真的算不错了
But reaIIy, I can't compIain.
拉娜?
Lana?
克拉克?
Clark?
对不起 我有别的朋友来 要去打个招呼
WouId you excuse me? There's someone I'd rea y Iike to say he Io to.
拉娜?
Lana?
- 拉娜?真高兴见到你 - 克拉克
- Lana Lang? It's great to see you. - CIark.
- 你看来师极了 - 不 你才是…
- You Iook wonderfuI. - Me? No, you Iook...
- 我来帮你 - 不用 我自己可以
- Let me g ve you a hand with that. - No, no. I can manage.
Uh....
这是自从你妈过世后 你第一次从大都会回来
This is the first time you've come back since your mom passed away.
对的 对不起
Yeah. I'm sorry.
我听说是你和…
CLARK: I heard that you and...
- 唐诺分手了? - 你吃了没?
- ...DonaId sp it up. LANA: Did you eat yet?
还没
No.
借过 对不起 抱歉
Beg your pardon. Excuse me. Sorry.
- 这个不对 - 不对?
- That's not right. - No?
我和唐诺的事你说得对… 不过 你替我拿一下
You're right about DonaId and me, but... HoId this, okay?
当然
Oh, sure.
嗨 肯特
Hi, Kent.
嗨 你好吗?
Hi. How you doing?
对不起 我竟然弄错了 谢谢
I'm sorry. I'm going nuts. Thanks.
- 克拉克 - 是
- CIark. - Yeah.
拉娜
Lana.
Uh-oh. Um....
哦 甜心
BRAD: Hey, sweet.
我来了
Here I am.
记得你当选为舞会皇后 一票人等着要和你跳舞
Remember when you were prom queen? AII these guys were wa ting for a dance?
现在只剩下一个人了
There's on y one guy on your dance card now. Huh, honey?
- 真是美好的… - 布莱德威尔逊
- That's good oId... - Brad W son.
- 嗨 布莱德 - 嗨 肯特
- Hi, Brad. - Hi, Kent.
好久不见
Long time no see.
你懂吧 〝不见〞?
You know, see, see, see?
- 来吧 拉娜 - 不行
- Come on, Lana. - No, I can't .
克拉克他先请我的
- CIark aIready asked me. - I did?
- 我有吗? - 有 对不起
- Yeah. - Oh, excuse me.
拉娜 我好久没跳…
Lana, I haven't danced...
[SLOW MUSIC PLAYS]
（维斯寇集团 收支处）
高曼 又一星期又一张支票
Ah, Gorman. Another week, another check.
你有没有另外一张支票要给我? 我申请了公费
Don't you have another one for me? I put in a voucherfor expenses.
什么?
What?
有
Yeah, yeah.
拿去
Here you go.
（给付给 格斯高曼）
(8万5千7百89点9元）
谢谢你帮我收拾
Thanks for heIping me out.
你别客气 拉娜 很多人羡慕我有机会帮你
You kidding? A ot of guys wouId Iike to be where I am.
你会讶异我根本没有成觉到
You'd be surprised at how many offers I didn't get.
甚至布莱德都不会留下
Even Brad wouIdn't stick around.
真是不容易
It reaIIy isn't easy.
这些长幡?你只要…
The streamers? Yeah, you just pu , and...
不是这些长幡 是全部的
No, not the streamers. Everything.
不是我要抱怨 只是…
Not that I'm compIaining. It's just that...
我不知道为什么 我觉得我可以和你谈心
...I don't know why, I just feeI I ke I can taIk to you.
什么?
What?
我觉得我可以和你谈心
I fee Iike I can taIk to you!
- 是吗? - 是的
- You can? - Yes.
- 你知道吗 拉娜? - 什么?
- You know something, Lana? - What?
我一直…
I aIways....
我一直希望你会
I aIways wished that you wou d.
甚至在高中时代
I mean, even back in high schooI.
- 记得你是… - 舞会皇后
- Remember when you were...? - Queen of the prom.
经过三年的婚姻 他退出了
Then three years after the royaI wedding, the king abdicated.
- 这是不是太糟了吗? - 的确是
- Isn't that terrib e? - Yeah, sure is.
肯定剩下一大堆的洋芋沙拉
There must be a gaIIon of potato saIad eft over.
你知道问题所在吗?
You know what the probIem is?
不知道 是太多美乃滋了吗?
I don't know, too much mayonnaise?
唐诺喜欢吃美乃滋 这不会有问题的
Dona d oved mayonnaise. Why wouId that be the probIem?
问题是为什么我要留在小镇?
No, the probIem is, why do I stay in SmaIIv I e?
相信我 我一直这样自问
BeI eve me, I've asked myseIf that.
你知道你有多幸运能住在大都会? 人人向往的地方
Do you know how Iucky you are to Iive in MetropoIis? The B g Apricot.
那你可以…
WeII, Lana, you couId...
说来容易 我不能不顾瑞奇
Easy to say. But how? What about Ricky?
- 瑞奇? - 我儿子
- Ricky? - My IittIe boy.
- 你的 这不错 - 是
- You? Oh, that's great. - Yeah.
在这里 我们有一栋房子 我有工作可以支付帐单
I mean, at east here we have a house and I've got a job that pays the biIIs.
但是去年冬天开始 燃料帐单就变得越来越贵
Except for Iast winter when the fueI biIIs kept going up and up.
我甚至把结婚钻戒拿去当了
Yeah. Even had to pawn my diamond ring then.
那真可惜
That's a shame.
[CLARK WHISTLES]
你还没有结婚吗?
You never got married?
- 我吗? - 是啊
- Me? - Yeah.
我…
WeII, I was...
还没
No. Not....
[PLAYS PIANO]
你知道吗? 几年后再看到某人就会想…
You know, years Iater you can Iook at someone and think:
我想 那就是我错过的机会
''WeII, I guess that's the one that got away."
（罗斯维斯伯）
再说一次 我要再听一次
Give me that again, oId buddy. Run t by me just one more time.
- 八万五千元 - 不见了
- E ghty- five thousand doIIars. - Missing?
一笔完整的钱 从公司中被侵占
EmbezzIed, Mr. Webster. StoIen from the firm.
谁干的?
[Vera] By whom?
我要知道是谁干的?
That's what I want to know. By whom? Whom?
佛莅 控制一下自己吧
[Webster] Vera, get ahoId of yourseIf.
从未有人敢如此做
Nobody eIse ever wiII.
我不知道
SIMPSON: I don't know.
是谁呢?
Whom?
在往日事情简单得多
In the oId days it was simpIe.
我们有帐簿 有收据 哪一笔帐出去 哪一笔帐进来
We kept books, we knew what was go ng in and what was paid out.
即使有人要抢钱
If somebody wanted to rob you...
他们都带着枪进来说 把钱装进去
...they'd come in w th a gun and say, "Stick them up."
现在这些人利用后杂的电脑 做这种下流事情
Now they get bIasted computers to do their dirty work.
我的老朋友 你成为老古董了
My oId friend, you are yesterday.
至于谁做了此事 将会是明日之星
Whoever puIIed this caper is tomorrow.
维斯伯先生 该是你按摩的时候了
Mr. Webster, it's time for your massage.
这种女人怎能突然闯进来
Does th s woman have the right to burst in...?
等等 佛莅 辛普森 这位是我物理治疗师
Now, now, Vera. Simpson, you know my psychic nutritionist?
- 哈罗 - 抱歉 我们正要在此闻会
- He o. - We are trying to hoId a meet ng here.
你为何不省省力别讲话 这样很容易血压上升
Why don't you ho d your breath instead. Maybe you'lI turn bIue.
- 没水准 - 注意 我正要取你的人命
- Improvement. - I'm about to take a human Iife.
辛普森 请你回避几分钟好吗?
Simpson, wouId you excuse us for a second, pIease?
[ARGUING INDISTINCTLY]
- 闭嘴 用耳听 - 她是一只大肥猪
- Mouths cIosed. Ears open. - She's a big pig.
我不容许不服从我的人 和我一起
I can't have anyone with me who isn't with me.
好了 女孩们
Now, girIs.
辛普森
Simpson.
老朋友 现在该如何呢?
WeII, o d chum. What now?
就让八万五千块飞走吗?
Kiss the 85 thou goodbye?
持续让他得手 以为这是摇钱树吗?
Keep on paying the thief his saIary untiI he shakes the money tree again?
- 他迟早会露出马脚的 - 为什么?
- He's bound to sI p up sooner or Iater. - Why?
我也不知道 在电影中常是这样演的
That's what they aIways say in the mov es.
他不会不露马脚的 不会的
He won't sIip up at aII. No, not at aII.
他一定会继续从我的口中 不断地偷食我的面包
He'II keep quietIy taking the bread from our mouths.
他一定会不断地做 越陷越深露出马脚
He'lI keep a Iow profiIe and won't do a thing to ca attention to himseIf.
当然 除非他真是一位天才罪犯
UnIess, of course, he s a compIete and utter moron.
[TIRES SCREECH]
我先选 安德鲁
BOY 1 : I'II go f rst. Andrew.
- 我选克立思 - 你准备好了吗?
BOY 2: I'lI pick Chris. LANA: You feeI good? You feeI ready?
瑞奇 你的球鞋
LANA Ricky, your shoe.
- 我们要和瑞奇一组吗? - 你们猜拳输了
- You mean, we've gotta take Ricky? - You guys Iost the toss.
好吧 瑞奇
AII right, come on, Ricky.
- 等等 - 祝好运
LANA: Wa t, wait... - Come on, good Iuck.
- 我真受不了这样 - 拉娜 没事的 相信我
- I just can't stand this. - Oh, Lana. It'lI be okay.
我自己也是大器晚成
I know, I was a Iate bIoomer myseIf.
我不是因为他年纪小 他是镇上唯一没父亲的小孩
It's not just that he's sma I, he's the onIy kid in town wthout a father.
看看 才下午就醉醺醺了
Oh, Iook. He's stewed to the giIIs in the midd e of the afternoon.
- 我只喝了巧克力牛奶 - 不 我是指他
- Gee, aI he had was chocoIate miIk. - No, him.
甜心
Hey, sweet thing.
小朋友在比赛了
L ttIe k d getting hass ed, huh?
- 肯特 你也在这儿? - 是啊 布莱德
- Kent, you stiII here? - I seem to be, Brad.
他只需要有冠军经验的人 指导一下就好了
AII he needs s a few pointers from the oId champ here.
我参加了两年的 全国保龄球巡回比赛
I won the aII- country bowIing trophy two years in a row.
这我还不知道
I didn't know that.
天生有运动细胞的人 什么运动都会
Yeah. NaturaI athIete can pIay any sport.
布莱德 你只会搞砸
Brad, you're just gonna make it worse.
- 没关系 没事的 - 克拉克 他会搞砸的
- It's aII right. It'II be okay. - He'lI make t worse.
[BOYS GRUMBLE]
你看着 他会补进的
You watch, he'II get a spare.
加油 瑞奇
Come on, R cky.
孩子 你球拿错了
Hey, kid, you're hoIding it aII wrong.
- 让我示范一次给你看 - 布莱德
- Let oId Brad show you how it's done. - Brad.
对不起 布莱德 我想最好还是让孩子他自己打
Excuse me. Say, Brad, I think maybe he'lI be better off doing t his way.
你这种不入流的人 话还真多
For a guy Iucky to be waterboy, you've got a big mouth.
我只想说瑞奇不会希望 在同伴面前 被指导如何打球
I don't think he needs a esson in front of the other kids.
- 他需要有人教他 - 他会没事的 抱歉
- He needs a man to show him. - He's doing just fine. Excuse me.
去吧 瑞奇
Here you go, Rcky.
尽全力 好吗?去吧
And g ve it your best shot. Okay? There you go.
抱歉
Sorry.
Ah-choo!
[BOYS SHOUT]
保重啊
Gesundheit.
谢谢
Thank you.
格斯 老板要见你
Hey, Gus, the boss wants to see you.
他一直在看着我 你好吗?老板
He can see me aII right. HeIIo, Mr. Lewis.
不是那位老板 是大老板
No, not that boss. The boss.
你是说大老板
- You mean, the boss... - Yup.
要见我?
- ...wants to see me? - Yup.
他要见我干什么?
Oh, my God, why wouId he wanna see me?
我是说…
I mean....
老板要见我干什么?
Why wouId the boss wanna see me?
没有原因吗?
There's no reason.
那为何他…?我知道了
Then why'd he...? Oh, I know!
一定是关于 我对排球制服的意见
It's my suggestion for the voIIeybaII un forms.
就是这样
That's it.
罗斯老板…老板
Ross the boss. Ross the boss. The boss!
冷静 镇静 要坦然
Be caIm. Be cooI. Be coI ected.
维斯伯先生…?
Mr. Webster? Mr. Webster?
维斯伯先生 我…维斯伯先生
Mr. Webster, I did not... Mr. Webster.
格斯高曼先生吗?
[Webster] Mr. August Gorman?
先生 我就是高曼
GUS: August Gorman here.
我知道你心肠很好 我不要坐牢
I know you're a man of compassion, and I don't wanna go to jaiI...
因为他们那里有 强盗犯 强奸犯
...because they have robbers and rapists...
我只是要问你一个问题
I just wanna ask you one question.
你是一个很顽皮的人 是吗?
You've been a naughty guy, haven't you?
说良心话吧
Come on, adm t it now.
你在工作上常有一点顽皮 是吗?
You've been just a ittIe bit naughty, haven't you?
- 我是那一种… - 好了 不用多说
- I was kind of... - That's aII right. I understand.
我可以了解年轻人 现在的心态
I can... What do the young fo ks say today?
梦想出人头地的心情 兄弟
''Dig where you're coming from, brother."
你想要发财 是吗?
- You wanna be rich, right? - How, wha...
我一出生便注定富有 从不重后穿同一双袜子
I was born rich. Never worn the same pa r of socks tw ce.
那你怎样处理那些袜子?
GUS: What do you do with your socks?
拿去洗了“巴 送给慈济了吧
I don't know. They're Iaundered and sent to some charitable institution, I think.
我不知道或许变成别的了
ActuaIIy, I don't know. Maybe they turn them into dust rags...
或许是立可白
...or pen- wipers or something.
或许是袜子
Or maybe socks.
是的 我从不管这些
Yes! That never occurred to me.
格斯 你知道你的确是一位天才
Gus, you know something? You're a genius.
一位顽皮的天才 但又如何 没有人是十全十美的 干杯
A naughty genius, but what the heII? Nobody's perfect, right? Cheers.
是因为我用电脑 把半毛钱转出来的事
Because of the ha f- cent thing with the computers.
不…是因为电脑控制了 今日整个世界
No, no, because computers ruIe the worId today.
而控制电脑的人可以控制世界
The feIIow that can fooI the computers can ruIe the worId h mseIf.
我一直都在物色一位 能成功地利用电脑的人
I've been searching for somebody who can make these mach nes...
做人所不能的事 你明白我的意思吗?
...do what they're not supposed to. Get my drift?
- 明白  - 格斯…
GUS: Yes! - Gus...
维斯寇集团 维斯寇工业 是一个家族的大企业
...Webscoe, the Webscoe industriaI compIex, is a famiIy- owned carteI.
有些是要探测镁矿 有些要找锌矿
Some magnesium here, some z nc there.
铁路 农业机械 你在听吗?
RaiIroads, farm machinery. You foIIow me?
我在听
GUS: I foIIow you, sir.
- 格斯 你知道我想要什么吗? - 不知道
- Gus, do you know what I want now? - No.
我要咖啡
I want coffee.
需要奶 糖 还是…?
AII rght. BIack, cream, sugar, or...?
不是 你似乎不明白
No, you don't seem to understand.
众多不同的公司品牌 我要控制咖啡的价格
Under different company names, I controI the price of coffee beans...
在委内瑞拉 巴西 玻利维亚 牙买加 加彭共和国
...in VenezueIa, BraziI, BoI via, Jamaica and the RepubIic of Gabon.
但是 我现在有一个问题 你大概可以帮我解决
But I've got a probIem and I think maybe you can heIp me.
就是有一个国家不赏我的脸 我想你知道这有多丢脸
One country won't pIay baII with me. You know how that can bug a guy, rght?
不赏脸… 那个国家?
That couId bug... What country?
哥伦比亚 哥伦比亚?
- CoIomb a. - CoIomb a?
哥国是极重要的 咖啡进出口国家
CoIombia has two mportant exports, and one of them's coffee.
我试过多次 相信我 我真的试过多次
And I've tried to reason w th them. BeIieve me, I've tried.
但这真是令人难过的 固执国家
But this one miserabIe, pissant IittIe country...
以为可以阻碍了我的目标 不让我独占这个市场 格斯…
...has the gaII to th nk it can dictate the economy of an open market. Gus.
格斯 我的朋友
Gus, my friend...
我们要给他们一个教训 对吗?
...we're going to teach them a Iesson, aren't we?
毁掉哥伦比亚所有的咖啡田
Destroy the entire CoIombian coffee crop...
令他们成为不毛之地
...right down to the Iast bean.
- 不毛之地?我们? - 没错
- The Iast bean, we are. - Right.
但你拥有这么多了…
But you got so much. You know, Iike...
你知道为什么有人曾说 我想说的人真是独具慧眼
A wise man once said, I think it was AttiIa the Hun:
〝成功还不足够
''lt is not enough that I succeed.
必须其他人都失败〞
Everyone eIse must faiI."
有道理
Seems fa r.
- 格斯 - 什么?
- Gus. - What?
你要为我做这件事
You are going to do this for me.
- 怎么做? - 利用天气
- How? - The weather.
你没有告诉我你妈妈会来
You d dn't say your mother was here.
我是他的妹妹 他最小的妹妹
I'm his sister. His baby sister.
格斯 告诉我 难道你从未听过华根吗?
Gus, teII me, have you ever heard of VuIcan?
嗨 华根小姐
Hi, Ms. VuIcan.
华根是气象卫星 是政府设在…
VuIcan is the weather sate te our government put up...
运行轨道中 监视气象变化用的
...to mon tor the weather.
但如果有人能重新输入程式 它便能发挥更大的功效
But if somebody were to reprogram it, it couId do much more.
可以制造天气的变化
It couId make weather.
风暴或洪水
[Webster] Storms and fIoods.
暴风雪 热浪
[Vera] BIizzards, heat waves.
要怎么做?
How do you do that?
就像二十世纪 每一件事的作法一样
Like everyth ng e se in the 20th century, Gus.
你只要用按按几个键就行了
You push buttons.
[SHUTTER CLICKS]
- 好了 - 这是我一生中第一次赢得东西
- There you go. - It's the f rst time I won anything.
你赢得我的芳心 莫瑞
You won my hand, Maury.
对 但这是我第一次 赢得有价值的东西
But this s the first time I won anything vaIuab e.
戴上草帽会更像样
Let's get one wth the sombreros.
怀特先生 你过来把机票交给他们
Mr. White, you'II be in this, handing them the r pIane tickets.
- 为什么总要我做这种事? - 为什么总要我做这种事?
- Why do I have to do this? - Why do I have to do this?
你 你没被开除算运气好 本来有独家的…
You're Iucky I d dn't fire you. I get a chance at exc usive photos...
史上最大化学工厂火灾的照片
...of history's biggest factory fire.
回来时腿断了 照片也熔化了
He comes home with a broken Ieg and 12 meIted roIIs of fiIm.
因为热度太高
It was hot.
笑一笑 怀特先生
SmiIe, Mr. White.
南美洲 我不敢相信我的运气
South America! I can't beIieve my Iuck!
注意 你想要做但不被人发现…
See, f you don't want them to trace it back...
得找个隐密不引人注意的基地 装置一台电脑
...you've gotta punch in to some IittIe rinky- dink outfit...
一台小但功能多的电脑就行
...that has a IittIe Mickey Mouse computer...
你可以藏身的地方 是吗?
SomepIace you can sneak nto, rght?
有人可以”"'
Somebody couId...
那个地方没有人认识他 他们此不会怀疑他和我们有关
SomepIace where nobody knows him so they can't connect him with us.
维斯寇集团有112家子公司
Webscoe has 1 12 subsidiaries.
所有电脑系统都和中央电脑连线
They're aII I nked into the centraI computer system.
要找一个…这种地方
How about somepIace...
小地方?
...smaII?
（小麦之王 小镇）
小镇 小镇到了 停留五分钟
DRIVER: SmaIIviIIe. Th s is SmaIIviIIe. We' have a five- minute stop here.
小心走路
Mind your step.
小 。楼梯
Watch your step, pIease.
谢谢 席玛
Thanks, SeIma.
再见 拉娜 一天·险快
Thanks a Iot. Lana. Have a good day, now.
让我帮你 拉娜
CLARK: Let me heIp you, Lana.
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 谢谢 克拉克 - 你去坐下 巴士达 乖
- Thanks, CIark. - Sit down, Buster. Good boy.
坐下 巴士达 别乱动 乖
RICKY: Come on, Buster, sit down. That's a good boy.
你们都好了吗?很好
CLARK: Okay. You aII set? Great.
Wow.
我不再多说了
MAN: I'm not saying another word.
就这样
That's it. Okay?
天呀
Jesus Chrst!
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
你们在大都会也有郊游吗? 肯特先生
Don't they have picn cs in Metropo is, Mr. Kent?
有 只是和这里的不大一样
WeII, not quite Iike this, Ricky.
- 妈妈和我常一块出来郊游 - 真的
- Mom and I do this aII the time. - You do?
- 我帮你 - 瑞奇 别走远 要小心 好吗?
- I'II heIp you. - Stay cIose by and be carefuI, okay?
好的 妈妈
Okay, Mom.
来 巴士达 去找兔子 来 巴士达
RICKY: Come on, Buster. Let's find you a rabb t. Come on. Rabbit.
这样对他来说太好了
- This s so nice for him. - Here you go.
难得有一位男性在他身边 这对他的成长较好
It's even nicer when there's a man around, which sn't that often.
- 还有好多的选择机会 - 不 所有好的男人都结婚了
- There's a ot of cho ces. - The good ones are married.
所以布莱德以为 他是上帝给女人的礼物
That's why Brad thinks he's God's gift to women.
他不接受拒绝 但只有他自己在要求
He won't take no for an answer, but he's the onIy one asking.
不 拉娜 我还是觉得有很多选择的
No, Lana, I meant there's a ot of cho ces here.
这真是不错的郊游 有这种…
This is rea y qu te some picnic. There's ...
这个
...some of that.
绿东西
Green stuff.
豆泥
Hey, pate.
这种豆泥味道真特别
Boy, th s pate is reaIIy unusuaI.
我没有弄
I didn't make any... Oh, C ark.
这是巴士达的狗食物
That's Buster's dog food.
- 蛮好吃的啊 - 别再吃了
- It's good. - Don't eat it!
小狗什么时候吃?
What time's the dog eat?
- 真不错 - 拿去
- This is nice. - Here.
没关系的 拉娜
It's aII right, Lana.
谢谢
Thanks.
[BUSTER BARKS]
你去那里?回来 巴士达
Hey, where you go ng? Come on!
巴士达 不要闹了
Buster, stop messing about!
- 要待多久…? - 我正在想…
- How much Ionger...? - I was just thinking...
- 抱歉 请说 - 你说
- I'm sorry. No, go ahead. - No. You.
我只是在想…
WeII...
我在想 像你这样的人
...I was just thinking that...
一定可以在大都会发展
...somebody Iike you couId do reaI y weII in Metropo is.
我想我非得如此了 小镇里没有我要的了
I suppose I have to face it. I'm not gonna f nd what I want in Sma viIIe anymore.
可是…
我可以在大都会过活吗? 我能做什么工作?
Cou d I make it n MetropoIis? What wouId I do when I got there?
打电话给我
CaII me.
- 不 我不想打给你 - 你不想打给我?
- No, I wouIdn't wanna caII you. - You don't wanna caII me?
我想打给你 但我不想为你增加麻烦
Yes, I wanna caII you, but I wouIdn't wanna be a nuisance to you.
我从未想过你会为我增加麻烦
I don't think you couId ever be a nuisance to me, Lana.
克拉克 我可以告诉你件事吗?
C ark, may I teII you something?
我油箱正在漏油
My oiI pan is Ieaking.
看 有东西在漏
See? There's something dripping.
- 我可以帮上忙吗? - 不用 谢谢
- Can I give you a hand? - No, thanks.
由于车子太烂 我必须学会怎样修理车子
With a the car troubIe I have, I studied up on auto repair.
看看这个
Look at this.
天啊
CLARK: Oh, boy.
[CLARK HEARS BUSTER WHIMPERING]
拉娜 我去看看瑞奇怎样了 你没事吧?
Lana, I think I'II just go see if Ricky's aII rght. You okay?
嗯
Yeah.
天啊 他没事吧?
FARMER: Gosh, is he a rght?
嗨
Hi.
超人?
Superman?
就是我
That's me.
妈 妈
RICKY: Mom! Mom!
到了 他没事 女士 但最好还是给医生看看
There you go. He's aII right, but have a doctor check h m.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 我是拉娜 他是瑞奇 - 很高兴认识你们
- I'm Lana Lang. This is Ricky. - Nice to meet you.
- 瑞奇 - 这是克拉克
And this s C ark.
我真的要走了 再见瑞奇
I reaIIy have to be going. So ong, R cky. Bye.
妈 我们在天空飞
We were fIying, Mom!
你究竟在做什么?
What were you doing, anyway?
我在找巴士达
I was Iooking for Buster.
- 巴士达 巴士达  - 我找到他了
- Buster! Buster! CLARK: I found him!
好了 就这样
CLARK: Come on, boy. That's it.
肯特先生 超人刚在这里
Mr. Kent, Superman was here!
- 什么? - 是的 他真的在这儿
- What? - Yes, he reaIIy was.
你不觉得很兴奋吗?
Aren't you excited?
我在大都会的时候 我每天看到他
I'm from MetropoIis. I see Superman every day.
真的 你可否给我 他的亲笔签名
You do? CouId you get me his autograph?
我不知道 我需要打个电话给他…
I don't know. If had a nickeI for every time some ittIe kid....
[RINGS BUZZER]
是的…你要干什么?
Yeah? What do you want?
我们有麻烦了 不是吗?
We're in big troubIe, aren't we?
- 什么? - 我说我们麻烦大了…
- What? - We're in big troubIe.
首先是丢掉了所有的收据
First, they ost the invoice.
然后他们又找到了 却少了几项东西
When they found it, they reaIized they came up short on a few items.
所以我必须要租车 我错过四点到克里夫兰的飞机
So I rented a car because I missed the pIane from CIeveIand. 4:00, you know.
在路上又爆胎了 真·廖
And a fIat tire on the highway. What a kicker.
我必须自己去处理这些
Had to fix it myseIf with these IittIe p nkies.
而我想你的老板真的会气死 你懂吗?
And I figured your boss was gonna be reaI peeved, you know what I mean?
你在说些什么?
What do you mean?
他将会把我们钉在墙上
He is going to hang our butts against the waII.
他要这个特殊订购
He wanted this specia order instaIIed...
明天早上以前在他办公室装好
...in his office no Iater than tomorrow morning.
所以你必须让我进去 因为我今晚就得安装
Let me in because I gotta set it up tonight.
要安装什么?
Get a I what set up?
兄弟 你真的是救世主 你真的是救世主
PaI, you are a rea Iifesaver. I mean, a reaI Iifesaver.
- 办公室怎么去? - 直走
- Which way's the off ce? - Straight on ahead.
- 跟我走 - 我就在你身后
- FoIIow me. - I'm right behind you.
好耶
Oh, yeah.
有些不错…很好…
BRAD: Not bad. It's pretty good.
你知道新加坡的翼酒 有什么不好吗?
You know what's wrong with this Singapore wing?
滑酒 是新加坡滑酒
GUS: SIing! S ngapore SIing.
有什么不对吗?
What's wrong with t?
这里面的伏特加不够
There's not enough vodka in it.
这里面没有伏特加
There's no vodka in it!
这就是我要告诉你的 加些伏特加进去
What did I teII you? Put some vodka in it.
这是你要的 你知道的
What did you...? You know.
现在这里面有伏特加了
- Yeah. - There's vodka in it now, buddy.
对…太好了
Yeah, perfect.
- 你从未喝昏过吧? - 没有…
- You never do pass out, do you? - Nope.
从未
Never.
做得好 兄弟
Job we done, buddy.
你以为我也喝醉了 是吗?
You thought I was drunk too, didn't you? Ha, ha.
骗到你了
Foo ed you.
把钥匙给我…
Get the keys, get the keys.
[YELLS]
（禁止进入 授权者才可通行）
有人喝醉了
Somebody's drunk.
哈罗宝贝…
HeIIo, baby!
哈罗 小宝贝
How's the ittIe baby?
好了
Okay.
好…好了…开始干活吧
AII rght, et's get down to it. Let's do it.
1…2…按钮…
One, two, button your shoe.
两把钥匙要同时插
"Both keys at the same time"?
Whoa.
等…等一下
Wait. Wait a minute.
你以为你赢了?
Think you've won, don't you?
戏法人人会变…
The PhiIIy FIash!
[MAKES CAR NOISES]
好 准备好?
Okay, ready?
1 2 3
One, two, three!
（哈罗）
现在我们看看有什么
Yeah. Now we' see what we'II see.
[CHUCKLES]
[COMPUTER BEEPING]
（布鲁明岱尔百货）
Oh.
Oh....
（布鲁明岱尔百货）
（应缴金额 17万6千7百84点57元）
Oh.
[COMPUTER BEEPING]
[HORNS HONK AND PEOPLE SHOUT]
快 拜托
Come on, pIease.
就这样
There it is!
现在 哈罗
He o! Now...
开始做事了
...getting down to bus ness.
我是天才
I am a genius.
我是…
I am a....
（座标设定：)
（高温程式…扫描地球）
经度…
Longitude...
还有其他的纬度 对吧?
...and the other thing. Latitude, rght?
（经度：75度 纬度：5度）
（位置…哥伦比亚：南美洲）
你看 莫瑞 当地的婚礼仪式
Oh, Iook, Maury. A native wedding.
（西班牙文）
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
没有一个同事 告诉我们现在是雨季
No one said at the Dally Planet that this was the rainy season!
[INDISTINCT CHATTER AND SHOUTING]
气象学者非常地疑惑 飓风加上猛烈的大雨
NEWSCASTER: Meteorologists are baffled by the tornado and ralnstorms...
今天下午肆虐南美洲的哥伦比亚
...that struck the country of Colombia this afternoon...
完全摧毁咖啡田 影响未来五年咖啡的生产
...threatening to destroy the nation's entlre coffae crop for the next flve years.
瞬问强风…
Gale- force wlnds up to...
高达时速250英里 冲击到所有村庄
...an incredibIe 250 miIes an hour Iashed the countryside...
同时在当天雨量达12英寸
...whiIe 12 inches of rainfa have aIready been recorded in just one day.
我引述 气象局发官人的话
A spokesman for the Department of Meteorology said this was, l quote.;
这是最可怕的自然力量…
"The most awesome dispIay of natural forcas slnce Noah's ark.''
我再笑下去我会歪一边
If I Iaugh any harder, I' I spIit my s des!
气象似乎已经违背了 所有的理论
...to dafy all laws of weather systems known to science.
真可惜
What a shame.
可怜的哥伦比亚
Poor Iitt e CoIombia. WeII....
[WEBSTER CHUCKLES]
[SCREAMS]
你真淘气 你这个大笨蛋
I'm gonna get you for that, you big s y!
老哥 你真的了解我们在干嘛吗?
Bubba, do you reaIize what we're on to?
了解吗?
[Webster] Do I?
以后所有人喝的咖啡 就是维斯伯咖啡
Every time a drunk sobers up, he'II dr nk Webster coffee.
为何要选咖啡?
Why stop at coffee?
一杯咖啡就可以让全世界 早上出门去上班
A cup of coffee gets the word off to work n the morning.
但又是什么让世界运作?
But what keeps the worId working?
低糖汽水?
Diet soda?
佛莅 你是说?你是说?
Vera, you mean...? You mean...?
今天是咖啡
Today, coffee.
明天此是石油
Tomorrow, the oiI!
- 石油? - 如果高曼可以正确地运用
- OiI? - If Gus can push the right buttons...
我就可以控制全世界的石油 天啊
I can have it aI . HoIy cats!
所有的石油
AII the oiI.
所有的油井
AII the pumps.
所有的油槽
AII the tankers.
这真是个不错的主意 佛莅
This is some nifty idea, Vera.
- 老板 - 非常不错
GUS: Boss? [Webster] Very nifty.
- 我正好要找你 - 老板…这不是我的错
- Just the man I want to see. - Boss, t is not my fauIt.
干得是不是很好…
Isn't it neat? There...
- 什么不是你的错? - 超人…
- What's not your fau t? - Superman.
我怎么知道 他会阻扰你的事情
How was I to know he was gonna start doing his th ng...
当你要这样做呢?
...when you started doing your thing?
- 你在说什么? - 我在说什么…
[Vera] What are you taIking about? - What am taIk...?
就是电视上播的 老兄 你没看到吗?
It was just on teIevision, man. Didn't you see it?
别叫我〝老兄〞
Don't caII me ''man.''
我看到哥伦比亚被毁了
I just saw CoIombia bite the dust. That's aII.
你没看到他从云端飞出来吗? 就是他
You d dn't see the man come f ying out of the sky from the c ouds? It was h m!
他的斗蓬飞扬 然后…
With h s cape fIapping in the...
他的斗蓬就是在飞扬
His cape was fIapp ng in the wind!
他在飞翔 真棒
He was fIying! He was great!
就这样飞
He was just fIying around....
就像这样穿过云层 就这样地飞
His cape was blowing ln the wlnd llke thls. lt looked like a flag!
然后他就降落在大农场的中问
And he Ianded right in the middIe of this big pIantation!
他就先用透视眼检查了状况
And he checked everything out wth his x- ray vision.
然后他用雷射眼 修后所有的东西
And then he put these Iaser beams out of his eyes onto everything.
用雷射修复
Straight- out Iasar points.
把所有的东西都弄干了
Drled up everythlngl
就在一瞬问
Just Iike that!
就像在厕所的烘手机一样
I'm taIk ng about dry ng it up. Iike machines in the men's rooms.
你知道我在说什么吧?
You know what I mean?
手放在下面热空气会出来 你可把手烘干
Hot air comes out when you put your hands under.
有时是没用
Sometimes they don't work, right?
而超人办到了
But Superman's worked!
你以为他在开玩笑吗? 这家伙不是
You think he stood around to take bows? Not th s man.
没有 他又飞走
No, sir. He fI es off again. R ght?
然后他看到了问题的所在
Then he saw what rea y caused the troub e.
他就飞向龙卷风
He flew into the tornado ...
从下面往上雅 他就把事情解决了
...went down to the bottom of it, and turned it upside down!
他使得龙卷风反转了
He made the little end on top and the big and on the bottom!
我快要疯了
I was gonna go crazy!
我从来没看过那样的东西
I've never seen nothing ike it.
把龙卷风阻止了…
The big end was on the bottom.
上下颠倒了
L ttIe end on the top.
罗斯先生…它说…很大…
Mr. Ross, it was... The b g....
超人太坏了
Superman's bad.
我说他是
I'II say he was.
我是说他很坏
I mean, he was bad!
不…
No.
不
No!
甜心 我来 我来帮你
Here, et me heIp.
- 完美的计划要有傻子愿意执行 - 而我们就是那种傻子
- It was a perfect pIan. It was fooIproof! - And we were the fooIs.
这不是我的错 我尽到本分了
It's not my fauIt. I did what I was supposed to do.
他破坏的  是个差劲的好人破坏的
He ruined it. That ousy do- gooder ru ned it.
现在他或许会破坏到 我的石油计划
Now that he's puIIed off this stunt, he'l try and ruin my oiI scheme too.
- 我必须要除掉他 - 要怎么做?
- I've got to get rid of him. - How?
开枪射他? 你知道他对子弹的承受度
Shoot h m? You know about him and buIIets.
- 氪石 - 什么?
- Kryptonite. - What?
气火子…还是气豆子?
Or krypton- ham, or krypton- heimer?
我不知道要怎么叫它 但是这玩意儿会干掉超人
I forget what you ca it, but it's stuff that can hurt Superman.
- 你怎么会知道的? - 我还是知道一些事情
- How wouId you know about that? - I know a few th ngs.
我知道了 从漫画书看到的
I know, from the graff ti I saw.
等一下…
[Webster] Wait a second.
她是对的
She's right.
氪石 我记得有一篇采访中 有提到这样东西
Kryptonite. I remember reading about t in an interview with him.
它是哪里来的?
[Vera] Where does it come from?
从超人来的星球上有氪石
[Webster] The same pIanet Superman came from: Krypton.
哪里找得到氮石?
[Vera] Where is Krypton?
找不到的
GUS: It's nowhere.
那星球几年前说炸掉了
It bIew up in space, years ago.
- 他们在超人小时候 就送他来地球了 - 对
- They sent Superman here from there when he was just a baby. - Right.
你看我知道一些吧
I know some things too.
等一下…你知道一个星球爆炸 会如何吗?
Wait a minute. You know what happens when a pIanet expIodes.
- 残骸 东西会飘到太空中 - 怎样?
- Debris. Th ngs fIoating in space. [Vera] So?
所以我们只要 找到氪石就行了
So aII we have to do is find out where in heaven Krypton used to be.
那我们只要让格斯在这里 用卫星去找就可以了
Then we get good oId Gus to contact the VuIcan sateIIite.
格斯已经在思考这些了
OId Gus has been doing some thinking.
很好 这就是我要你办事的原因
Good. That's why I keep you around.
是…我是在想我没有得到应有的报酬
Yeah. I've been thinking that I'm not making enough money for this g g.
格斯 我平生最痛恨的…
Gus, if there's anything I hate...
就是贪婪
...it's greed.
贪婪?罗斯先生 等一下
Greed? Mr. Ross, just a minute.
我要说的是…
Let me teII you something.
我不会滑雪
I can't ski!
[YELLS]
一旦格斯和华根卫星连上线
[Webster] Once Gus contacts the Vulcan satelllta...
就可以命令搜寻外太空
...he orders lt to search through spaca...
就可以找到氮石失落之处了
...around where Krypton went bya- bye.
（接受指令）
（扫描）
然后卫星很容易就可以找到氪石
Then the laser probe locks on to a floating chunk of Kryptonita.
由电脑分析成分后
The computer analyzes the components...
我们此可以在实验室里复制
...and the boys at the lab dupllcate tha stuff down hera.
〝未知〞?
GUS: "Unknown"?
"Unlknown "?
（低焦油 9毫克焦油）
（焦油 百分之0点57)
管他的 他又不会去吸它
What the heII, he ain't gonna smoke it.
（此合成物品为：氛石）
怀特先生无法对此事负责
SECRETARY: Mr. White can't be responsibIe.
他在哪里?
Where is he?
拜托啦 两位
PIease, Mr. Stokis.
他要付出代价
He'lI pay for this.
准备付钱吧 怀特先生
Get out your waIIet!
- 早安  - 别向我问早安
PERRY: Good morning. STOKIS: Don't you "good morning" me.
往日关系依旧
"OId, oId reIationships suddenIy seem very much the same.
学校中最美的女孩
The prettiest gir in the schooI...''
仍然是学校中最美的女孩
...is st the prettiest girI n the schoo .
[PHONE RINGS]
- 哈罗? - 哈罗 嗨 克拉克
- HeIIo? LANA: Hello. Oh, hl, Clark.
拉娜 嗨 我正在想你
Lana! H , I was just thinking about you.
Oh, um....
听着 瑞奇有些麻烦
Listen, I have a probIem with Ricky.
什么事情?瑞奇怎么了?
Why? What happened to Ricky?
就是你给他超人的签名 他真的很高兴
It's Superman's autograph you got him. He got carried away...
就告诉其他的孩子 超人会参加他下星期三的生日
...and toId the k ds Superman was coming on his birthday.
好 我知道这样不好
Okay, it was wrong...
但是… 如果星期三超人没有来…
...but when Wednesday comes and Superman doesn't show, it's gonna....
拉娜 这种情况 我想我可以去跟超人讲一下
WeII, Lana, in this case I th nk I can go ahead and speak for Superman.
我是说 他和我相当熟识
I mean, he and I are pretty cIose, you know.
你告诉瑞奇 超人下星期三会到的 好吗?
And you can te Ricky that Superman wiII be there on Wednesday, aII right?
他会尝到最道地的家乡菜 他会…
WeII, he's gonna get the best home- cooked meaI he's had...
垂涎三尺
... n a Iong time.
- 你告诉超人 我们觉得他很好 - 好
- Tell Superman we thlnk ha's wonderful. - A rght.
- 但是 克拉克… - 怎样?
- But, CIark... - Yeah?
你是最好的
...you're the best.
就算我要告到最高法院 也在所不惜
And I'II take it to the Supreme Court f I have to.
但是这不是我们的错 这是上帝的意思
But it wasn't our fauIt. It was an act of God.
在教堂里?
In a church?
嘿
SC ENTIST: Hey!
这是你要的组合物
Here's that compound you ordered.
我无法想像这是什么
Can't imagine what you want with it.
但是你可以拿去了
But you got it.
我在怕什么鬼? 我是地球人耶
What the heII am I afraid for? I'm from Earth.
[MARCHING BAND PLAYS]
拉娜 我真的不知道会这样
SUPERMAN: Lana, I reaIIy wasn't expect ng a this.
我想他们真的想做一些事
I guess they did get a ttIe carried away.
（欢迎超人 小镇）
（欢迎）
超人 我们都知道
Superman, we aI know...
你并不期望被表扬
...that you're not ooking for honors and awards.
但是当我们听到你要来此 找你的好友瑞奇
But when we heard that you were coming to see your paI Ricky...
我们此想这是 我们向你说谢谢的好机会
...we reaIized that this was our chance to say thank you.
首先是扑灭化学厂的大火
First, for putting out the Lake Comooga fire.
还有你救了瑞奇一命
And not east, for saving IittIe R cky.
既然你已经 在我们的心中占有一席之地
So since you aIready have the key to our hearts...
超人…
...Superman...
容许我在此向你献上市钥
...may I present you with the key to the city.
谢谢
Thank you, s r.
Thank you.
[HONKS HORN]
你们都在
As you were.
现在听好
Now Iisten up.
我刚刚
I just came in d rectIy...
从五角大厦过来
...from the Pentagon...
你们最好相信我来此的原因
...and you better beIieve there's a damn good reason that I did.
因为上帝给了我们
Because God has given us...
世界上最好的礼物
...one of the greatest gifts in the worId:
化学
ChemicaIs.
你们这些人 在星期天去做礼拜 是吗?
Now, you peopIe, you Iike to go sit in church on Sunday, don't you?
你们喜欢坐着看超级杯比赛
You Iike to sit and watch the Super BowI.
是
CROWD: Yeah.
而你们坐在什么上面?
Sit on what?!
你们是坐在做好的塑胶椅上
You sit on moIded, pIastic seats!
这样此可以让你们好好地坐
MoIded to your we - fed behinds.
现在我不需要告诉你们 美国在这方面的
Now, I don't have to teII you that America Ieads the worId...
领先程度
... n high- grade pIastics.
我们无法承受 化学塑胶的差距
We cannot afford a chemica - p astics gap.
现在 听我说…
Now, isten to me.
你想要…
Do you want...
我们的美国总统坐下来
...our president of the United States sitting down...
写一篇和平条约
...to write a peace treaty...
让他的原子笔爆开后
...and have h s baIIpoint pen bust open...
墨水弄脏他的 好看又干净的裤子
...and the ink run out aII over his nice, cIean pants...
在全世界的领袖面前出挨吗?
... n front of the worId Ieaders?
不…
CROWD: No. No.
现在我们都知道
Now, we a know...
上星期全世界半数的国家
...that Iast week, haIf of this great nation of ours...
都遭受灾难
...aImost bit the buI et...
如果不是他 后果不堪设想
... f it wasn't for this man here.
[CHEERING]
我只能说成谢上苍 赐予我们超人
And aI I can say is, thank the Lord for Superman.
超人 你解救了我们
Superman, you saved our bacon...
而我要表达我的成激
...and I'd Iike to show our gratitude.
小小意思 不成敬意
This s a smaII token of our appreciation...
成谢你让我们避免了 一场化学大灾难
...to show to you for saving us from a chemicaI- pIant disaster.
将军 非常成谢
Thank you very much, generaI.
这真好 谢谢
This is very nice. Thank you.
[CROWD CHEERS]
[MARCHING BAND PLAYS]
非常好
It's very n ce.
〝未知〞 我要如何知道 什么是〝未知〞?
Unknown. How am I supposed to know what ''unknown'' means?
〝未知〞就是没有人会知道
It means unknown. It means nobody knows what it means.
- 哈罗 老板? - 格斯?
- HeIIo, boss? [Webster] Gus?
- 我是格斯高曼 - 我知道 情况如何?
- Gus Gorman here. - l know that. How did it go?
是 你知道他们在找 烹调上的秘密
You know how they're aIways trying to find the secret recipe...
有多难吗?
... n that ch cken in the bucket?
而似乎没有人知道配方
And nobody seems to know the ingred ent...
因为有〝未知〞的成分
...because t's unknown, right?
氪石也有一个不知道的成分 还有…超人没有死
In the Kryptonite there was an unknown eIement and Superman didn't die.
他没有死
He didn't die.
我要你去杀超人…
I ask you to kiII Superman...
而你却告诉我 你无法做到这种简单的事情
...and you're teIIing me you cou dn't even do that one s mpIe thing.
哈罗?
He o?
[BUSTER WHIMPERING]
[BUSTER BARKING]
他好久没有睡午觉了
He hasn't had an afternoon nap for years.
我想今天是他最重要的日子 而我不知要如何成谢你
This is the biggest day of h s Iife. I don't know how to thank you.
那顿丰富的午餐已经表达谢意
You d d with that wonderfuI Iunch.
我是喜欢煮饭烧菜
Oh, weII, I do Iike to cook.
- 你喝咖啡吧? - 好 谢谢
- You'lI take some coffee? - Yes, pIease.
- 低咖啡因的 - 对
- Decaffe nated, of course. - Right.
[PHONE RINGS]
哈罗?是
Hello? Yes.
什么?
What?
真的吗?
Oh, reaIIy?
是 他在这里
Yeah, he's here.
我会告诉他 好的 谢谢 再见
I'II teII him. Okay, thanks. Bye- bye.
超人 我的朋友贝蒂说
Superman, that was my frend Betty.
河流的桥上发生意外 一部卡车出了车祸
There's an accident on the br dge. A traiIer crashed through the raiI.
车子悬在桥上 司机还在里面
It's hanging off the bridge and the drver's in the cab.
很抱歉 我不是要赶你
I'm sorry. I hate to make you rush off.
一点都不赶
WeII, there's no rush.
- 但是在桥上… - 没关系 我会赶到的
- But the bridge... - It's okay. I aIways get there on time.
来啊 我们休 急一下
Come on, et's re ax a IittIe.
要找到像你这么漂亮的 单身女孩很不容易
It's unusuaI finding a good- Iooking girI Iike you aIone Iike this.
听着 你确定桥那边没问题吗?
Listen, are you sure you shouIdn't do something about the brdge?
什么桥?
What bridge?
你说得对
You're right.
我必须要走了
I have to get going.
[SIREN WAILS]
把他弄出来 快啊
OFFICER: Get h m out of there. Come on.
快点弄出来
Get him out! Get him out qu ck!
弄出来 要掉下来了
Come on. Get him away. That thing's gonna go.
大家还好吗?
MAN: Everybody okay? Joe?
我能帮上什么忙吗?
What can I do to heIp?
现在没什么好帮的了
Not much of anything now.
如果你能早点来 就好了
If on y you'd got here a minute sooner.
（意大利文）
[SPEAKING ITALAN]
（超人 善良的抉择）
在一次特别的会议中
''At a speciaI session of the GeneraI AssembIy...
有178个国家投票谴责超人
...178 countries voted to censure Superman...
只有哥伦比亚一个弃权
...with onIy CoIombia absta ning."
我只能告诉你们
I can teII you one thing.
他在小镇并没有如此坏
He wasn't so mean and nasty the other day in SmaI viIIe.
事实上他真的很好
In fact, he was so fuII of niceness...
我不喜欢用这样的事情
...I hated Iaying that big chunk of....
氪石…
Kryptonite. Don't you see?
你没看出实验室的成果吗? 并没有完全失败
That stuff we ran off in the Iab wasn't a compIete faiIure after aII.
就在格斯给他这份礼物后 他就变得…
Right after Gus gave it to h m, he started to turn into...
卑鄙 邪恶 心怀不轨 自私
...an ornery, eviI, maIicious, se fish...
- 一个平常人  - 对
- A normaI person. - Yes.
而现在超人 就不会再做好事了
And now that Superman is out of the nice- guy business....
我们此可以进行石油计划了
We can get to work on that oiI.
[LAUGHS]
[BAND PLAYS AS PEOPLE CHEER]
现在是极为重要的时刻 最后一位跑者…
ANNOUNCER: And now, tha suprame moment, as the last runner...
以无比荣誉的心态 手持圣火…
...the one glven the great honor of lightlng the caramonial flame...
跑完了为时七天的马拉松…
...runs the last lag of a marathon that began seven days ago...
很多选手…
...as thls torch has been passed from athlata to athlete...
经过全国…
...for 970 mlles...
970英里
...across the country.
（《单纯原因的批判》 坎特）
他怎么能说单纯分类没有…
How can he say that pure categories have no objective mean ng...
重要的逻辑? 那综合性的连贯呢?
...in transcendentaI Iogic? What about synthetic un ty?
嗨 甜心 我妨碍到你了吗?
Hi, honey! Am I in your way?
- 在旁边看着或许你会学到什么 - 嗨 罗蕾莱
- Stick around, you may Iearn something. - Hi, LoreIei.
世界上所有的油轮 都由电脑控制
AII the o tankers in the word are totaIIy controIIed by computers.
电脑告诉他们要去哪里 要运多少油
They te I them where to go, how much oiI to pick up...
要去哪里
...and where to deIiver it.
他们在船上没船长吗?
Don't they have captains on these ships?
有 但是不需要他们
Yes, but they don't need them.
说起来真有点伤成
That's a throwback to some sentimentaI, seafaring baIoney.
你要下令这些油轮 朝一个在大西洋中央…
[Vera] You wiII command the tankers to saiI toward a 50- miIe area...
五十英里的区域去
... n the middIe of the At antic Ocean.
然后要做什么?
And do what?
什么也不做
And do nothing.
就待在那里
Just sit there.
那人们要如何得到石油?
How are aII the peop e gonna get their o ?
你反应真快 老兄
You catch on fast, oId buddy.
美国每一个油井都是由…
Every oiI pump in America is run by...
- 由电脑控制 我知道 - 你不要打断我
- Computers. know. - WiII you stop interrupt ng?!
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你要下令 所有的油井停止供油
You wiII command the pumps to stop pumping.
然后我要你设计一个 特别的程式
[Webster] Then I want you to program one speciaI command...
在所有的系统中
... nto aII these systems.
一个无法更改的程式
TeII them these orders are rreversibIe.
没有人能够再把它改回来
So t wou d be impossib e for anybody to switch them back.
你办得到吗 老兄?
Can you do this for me, o d buddy?
老友?
OId paI?
你一直要用你的方法去做
You know, you get your way a the time.
这是不对的
And it's not right.
我要知道我有什么好处
I wanna know when I get a taste.
我想你已经尝到 自由的滋味 不是吗?
I th nk you've aIready had a taste of freedom, haven't you?
还是你想要坐牢?
Or wouId you prefer jaiI?
你已经无法让我去坐牢了
You can't run that jaiI number on me.
因为我知道我在外面的价值
Because I know I mean more to you out here doing th ngs for you...
比在牢里面无所事事要高
...than sitt ng in jaiI doing noth ng for nobody.
我懂了
I see.
你要什么?
What do you want?
什么?垃圾?
What? A wastelbasket?
不 这是计划
No. These are pIans.
这是蓝图
BIueprints.
- 为什么? - 一部电脑
- For what? - A computer.
- 我们已经有电脑了 - 不 不是这样的
- We've a ready got computers. - No, not Iike this.
目前世界上 没有一个电脑能像这样
There's not a computer Iike this in the whoIe worId anypIace.
目前不存在的 你要知道…
It doesn't exist. You see...
我们必须去建造新的电脑
...we have to buiId it.
那它会做什么?
What wiII it do?
我所说的任何事情
Anything I teII it.
那对我有何好处?
What wi I it do for me?
对你而官?任何你告诉我的事 我都可以帮你做
For you? It wiII do anything you teII me to teII it to do for you.
LORELEI: Wow.
告诉我
TeII me.
首先如果任何人想要攻击它
GUS: F rst of aII, f anyone attacks this machine or anything...
电脑会自动反击
...the computer counterattacks it.
它会自动找到他们的弱点 解决对方
I mean, it f nds their weaknesses and wipes them out.
好 老友
[Webster] Right, old buddy.
你帮我处理石油 我就建一部电脑给你
You deal with my oil and l'll bulld you your machlna.
好 我会做
GUS: Okay, l'll do it.
只是我无法复原的程式 没有太大的把握
But l'm not so sure about thls lrravarsible business.
他们全部停工了 怎么搞的?
They aII kind of went... What the heI ?
就这样了 最后一艘油轮
[Webster] That's it. The Iast tanker.
他们全都是 全都是我的了
They're aII mine now. AII mine.
Yay.
并不是
[Vera] Not quite.
在上面那一个是什么?
What's that in the upper- middIe quadrant?
是油轮
It's a tanker.
它走错路了
And it's go ng the wrong way.
船长?
Skipper?
又来了 〝马上到…
There it is again. "Proceed immediateIy to...
北纬30度 西经45度
...Iat tude 30 north, Iongitude 45 west.
等待进一步的指示〞
There await further orders."
那是大西洋的中央
HeII, that's the middIe of the AtIantic.
我才不要把我的船闭到那里 等待什么指示
I'm not taking my ship there just to await further orders...
才不管上面说什么
...no matter what that says.
我们该去大都会 我们此去大都会
We're supposed to go to MetropoIis, and we're go ng to Metropo s.
好了
AII right.
她在那里
MAN 1: That's where she is. Yeah.
好了 到上面
MAN 2: Come on, get it up there.
小姐?
OFF CER [ON PA] Mlss?
小姐 你听到我了吗?
Miss, can you hear me?
听着 我们是到这里来帮你的
Llstan, we are hera to help you.
不要跳 我重复 不要跳
Don't jump. l rapeat, do not jump!
我以为你永远不会来此
Thought you'd never get here.
我希望你不会指望我来救你 因为我再也不这么做了
Don't expect me to save you. I don't do that anymore.
别担心
Don't worry.
我不需要被救
I'm Iong past saving.
[CHUCKLES]
嗯…
WeII...
别让我耽误你的事情
...don't Iet me keep you from anything.
我并没有其他的事情
I'm not in a rush.
你在想些什么?
What did you have in mind?
很多事情
Lots of things.
是吗?
Oh, yeah?
Ooo....
如果你可以帮我一个小忙
If you'II just do me one ittIe favor first.
要做什么?
What's that?
嗯…
WeII....
有一艘船
See, there's this Iitt e boat...
没有去该去的地方
...and it's not going where it's supposed to go and....
停止所有引擎
SAILOR: Stop aII engines!
Stop aII engines!
[EMERGENCY HORN BLOWS]
嗨
Hi.
要不要先来点前奏?
How about a I ttIe apres- ski?
香槟?
Champagne?
（限购2加仑）
不要插队
Take your turn I ke everybody eIse!
瑞 不要
Stop it!
他要过来了 摇上窗子
He's coming over here, Martha.
你不可以
MAN 1 : Don't you do that!
WOMAN: Don't ! PIease!
用包包打他啊
MAN 2: Hit him with your handbag!
救命 请救我 有人正在打我先生
HeIp me! PIease, heIp me. Somebody's beating up my husband.
- 我要去报警 - 杰克 你跟她去吧
- I've gotta caII the poIice. - Jack, go with her, okay?
这是今天第三次了 晚上会更糟糕
The th rd one today, and at n ght t's worse.
后面一定有人搞鬼
Somebody's behind this.
你别告诉我没有石油
You can't teII me there's no oiI.
你别告诉我 没有人因此发财
You can't say someone's not getting rich off this.
永远都会有人发财
Someone's aIways getting rich.
而你知道是谁受苦吗?小市民
You know who suffers? The smaII guy.
东部地区一片混乱 你们快点把东西弄进去
NEWSCASTER: Tha East Coast gets the brunt of the splll.
（维斯寇集团）
嘿 大伙 慢一点
[WORKERS SHOUT INDISTINCTLY]
不 我今晚不能跟你出去
No, I cannot go out with you tonight.
我明天晚上也很忙
No. I'm busy tomorrow night too.
是吗?要做什么?
Oh, yeah? Doing what?
我会想到一些 听着…
I'II think of something. Look...
- 我要走了 瑞奇需要我 - 拉娜
- ...I gotta go. Ricky needs me. - Lana.
布莱德 我告诉过你 不要再打给我了
Brad, pIease stop caIIing me. I've to d you!
你听我说
WeII, you Iisten to me, huh?
你最好要开始威谢我
You better start apprec at ng o d Brad.
否则你在小镇还能怎样?
What eIse you got in SmaIIv I e?
我在小镇能怎样?
What eIse have I got in SmaIIv e?
我想我有答案
I think I got the right answer.
我也是
So do I.
小镇机场 明天有飞机去大都会吗?
SmaIIviIIe Airport, what fIights do you have to MetropoIis tomorrow?
- 你要我放哪里? - 放在那里
- Where do I put this? - Over there.
- 这个你要我放哪里? - 放在那里
- Where do you want this? - Put it up there.
（圣路易旅社 小酒馆）
[PEOPLE CHATTER INDISTINCTLY]
你闻玩笑吗?我才不要进去
WOMAN: Are you kidding? I'm not going in there.
嘿 嘿 别这样
Hey, hey. Come on.
不要管他
MAN: Just Ieave him a one.
我过不去了 小姐 那里发生了事情
I can't get through. Someth ng's happening.
看 超人喝醉了
MAN: Hey, Iook! Superman's drunk!
- 我要看看这里发生了什么事 - 瑞奇…
- I wanna see what's happen ng here. - Ricky. Ricky!
- 瑞奇 - 对 没错
- Ricky. - Yeah, that's right.
- 谢谢 - 真可耻 真是的
- Thank you. - It's a disgrace, that's what it is.
我告诉你 没有人会再相信这个败类
I' I teII you, nobody's ever gonna trust that creep again.
他完蛋了
He's washed up.
你们在看什么?
What are you Iooking at? Huh?
对不起 超人?是我 瑞奇
RICKY: Excuse me. Superman? It's me, Ricky.
小镇的瑞奇
Ricky from SmaIIviIIe.
超人 告诉他们 你不会伤害任何人
TeI them you won't hurt anybody!
他变了
He's changed.
不 或许他只是生病了
No! Maybe he's just s ck.
超人 请好起来
Superman, pIease get better!
他没有听到你说的 瑞奇
LANA: He's not I stening to you.
他会听到 他听得到的 他有顺风耳
Yes, he s. He can hear me. He's got super- hearing.
超人 你只是陷入低潮
Superman, you're just in a sIump!
你会好起来的
You'II be great again!
你办得到的 超人
You can do it, Superman!
超人 你听得到我 对吗?
Superman, you can haar ma, can't you?
超人 你只是陷入低潮
Suparman, you're just ln a slump.
你会好起来的 你办得到的 超人
You'll be great agaln. You can do it, Superman.
超人 你听得到我 对吗?
Superman, you can haar ma, can't you?
[YELLS]
他疯了
MAN 1 : He's gone nuts!
快点
Come on!
[CHUCKLES]
我尽力了
I can g ve as good as I get.
是吗?好啊 来啊 快啊
Oh, yeah? A right, come on! Come on!
来啊 快啊
Come on! Come on!
（危险 强酸）
怎么了 肯特? 太热了吗?
What's the matter, Kent? Too warm for you, huh?
快点 懦夫 来抓我啊
Come on, chicken! Come and get me.
你已经把我给惹毛了
You've been on my nerves a Iong t me!
[GRUNTS]
[YELLS]
你一直想要飞起来 肯特
You aIways wanted to fIy, Kent.
现在机会来了
Now's your chance.
[CLARK YELLS]
[CLARK GRUNTS]
[GASPING]
船长…
Skipper!
天啊 你看看
God, wouId you Iook at that!
罗蕾莱小姐 目前不在家
[Webster] Mlss Loralel Ambrosia lsn't at home rlght now.
但是如果你有重要事
But lf you'd cara to laave a massage...
何不此当面跟她说呢?
...why not dellver lt to her ln person?
你终于展现出原来的你了
So you'va flnally shown your true coIors.
如果你想找我们 这里是你找到我们的地方
Wall, lf you're looking for us, here's where you'Il flnd us.
请快来
Do drop in.
这真好玩
[Lorelei] Wow, this is fun!
好玩?好玩的事情才开始
Fun? The fun's just starting.
等到超人找到我们 你们此会知道什么叫做好玩
Wait tiII Superman f nds us, then you'l see some fun.
等一下 你要搞超人?
Wait, you gonna mess with Superman?
走吧 我要在他进入陷阱前准备好
[Vera] Let's go. I want to be ready for him when he faIIs into our trap.
陷阱?
Trap?
我就是不懂你为何不能 像我们一样搭热汽球
I just don't see why you can't baIIoon down Iike the rest of us.
这…
WeII....
不可以…
No way.
我只是不相信人可以飞
I just don't beIieve a man can fIy.
小心点 马儿
[Lorelei] Watch out, horsy!
不要…
Don't , don't , don't .
不要想要飞
Just don't try to fIy.
别飞
Don't try to f y!
你不要档住我的路
WiII you get out of my way!
- 快 快点 - 我很快了
- Hurry! Hurry up! - I am hurrying.
- 我什么也看不到 - 把灯打开
[Lorelei] I can't see anything. [Vera] Turn on the Iight.
- 灯的开关在哪里? - 通常灯的开关在哪里?
[Lorelei] Where's the Iight switch? [Vera] Where do you usuaIIy find it?
我不知道 我检查一下入口处
[Lorelei] I don't know. I guess I'lI check the doorway.
天啊 这里真黑 这样好多了
God, it's pitch- bIack in here. Oh, that's better.
好棒的设备
Wow, what a jukebox!
我告诉过你们嘛 不是吗?
[Webster] I toId you, didn't ?
好了 这就是超极限电脑
There. The uItimate computer!
它会所有普通电脑会做的事情 还有其他电脑不会做的事情
It does everything a computer can do and 1000 things none of them can do.
来吧 让我们来试试看
[Vera] Let's give it a dry run.
等一下 我们要等格斯
[Webster] Wait a minute. We've gotta wait for Gus.
谁需要格斯?
[Vera] Who needs Gus?
- 只有他会控制电脑 - 简单得很
- He's the onIy one who can operate it. [Vera] Like fish he is!
我比博士都还了解 如何使用电脑
I know enough about computers to put a Ph.D. to shame.
拜托 老哥 你以为…
Come now, brother dear, you didn't think...
我真的会让那个小黑人玩吗?
...I was gonna Iet that IittIe man run the show, did you?
工人做好了 怎么不收拾好呢?
Why don't peons tidy up when they're done?
快点 老哥 好戏登场了
Come on, Bubba, t's showtime.
用那些按钮去启动阿法回路
Engage those buttons to act vate the aIpha circuit...
锁住系数
...and ock the moduIar grd.
你 放动29到W7处的线路
You! Activate circuits 29 through W- 7...
然后闲启全部能量 展闻防御系统功能
...and start fuII- power coordinates on exterior defensive systems.
换句话说 按红色按钮
In other words, push this red button.
你怎么知道的?
How did you know about that?
[BEEPING]
他来了
He's here!
很好 给他点事做做吧
[Vera] Good. Let's give him something to worry about.
现在我们来看看
Now, Iet's see....
导弹系统启动
Tracking systems ocked.
让游戏开始吧
Let the games beg n.
别太兴奋 甜心
[Lorelei] Don't tense up now, honey.
拜托 老哥 你在浪费火箭
[Vera] Come on, Bubba, you're wasting your rockets.
加油 超人
Come on, Superman!
把他干掉 罗斯
Let him have it, Ross.
（分数3400 火箭数21)
老哥 继续发射
[Vera] Bubba, keep f ring.
让他没时问顾到别的 我要准备飞弹
Keep him occupied whiIe I get the MX ready.
（飞弹 预备）
怎么回事?
GUS: What the heII is go ng on?
你继续发射火箭 等他发现飞弹说来不及了
[Vera] You keep your rockets coming. He won't notice the missiIe tiII too Iate!
（游戏结束）
你也不过尔尔
[Vera] So much for your cat ike ref exes.
天啊
Oh, God!
Ha, ha!
拜托…不要…坐
No more. Look, you sit.
对…坐下…
Sit, sit!
救命
HeIp!
哈罗 不要乱动
HeIIo? Forget you, jackass!
他就这样完了
[Webster] That's him out of the way.
老妹 你要控制全世界的武器系统吗?
Sis, how wouId you ike to controI aII the worId's weapons systems?
宝贝
Baby!
是老爸
It's Daddy!
你要对我的宝贝做什么?
Hey, what are you doing with my baby?
格斯 老搭档 上来一起玩吧
Gus, oId buddy, genius. Come up and join the fun.
他又过来了 启动内部防御
He's stiII com ng. Arm the inner defenses.
好了 维斯伯 游戏结束了
AII rght, the game's over.
嗨 甜心
Hi, honey.
我不认识你 小姐
I don't know you, Iady.
但是在那个晚上…
But the other night....
很抱歉 但是那不是我
I'm sorry, but that wasn't me.
那家伙走了
That guy's gone.
而你是下一位 维斯伯
And you're next, Webster.
千万别低估 电脑的力量
[Webster] Never underestimate the power of computers.
你喜欢吗?
How do you I ke it?
维斯伯 你就像其他人一样
SUPERMAN: I think it's typicaI of peopIe Iike you, Webster.
你们四个所做的 只是想满足自己的需求
Instead of heIping others, the four of you just wanna heIp yourseIves.
你们四个?
Four of you?
你说我们四个?等等
You mean, us? Four? Wait...
老兄…
Hey, man!
他只有一个名字 他希望别人称他〝超人〞
That's onIy his Iast name. He Iikes to be caIIed "Superman."
这样 我跟他们不同国 超人
See, I'm not w th them, Superman.
你是骗不了我的 先生
You couId've fooIed me, mister.
那个很好
[Webster] That's very good.
让我们看看没有空气 他能撑多久
[Vera] Let's see how Iong he can carry on wthout any a r.
[SUPERMAN GASPS]
他又来了  他要来抓我
He's sti I coming! He's going to get me!
才不会
Don't bet on it!
[SUPERMAN GROANS]
你在伤害他
You're hurting him.
- 那是氪石  - 是的
- That's Kryptonite! [Vera] Yes.
- 这一次我们做对了 - 你是个天才
- This time we got it rght! - You're a genius.
你所发明的机器 可以找到任何人的弱点
You've invented a machine that can find anybody's weak spot.
恭喜了 老弟
CongratuIations, oId buddy.
你将留名青史 因为你干掉了超人
You'II go down in history as the man who kiIIed Superman!
我不要
I'm... No.
超人
Superman!
不
No!
- 等一下…你以为你要去哪里? - 别管他了
- [Vera] Where do you think you're going?  - [Webster] Never mind.
- 增加能量 - 你不觉得他的能量够了吗?
- [Webster] Turn the power up.  - [Lorelei] Hasn't he had enough?
再增加
[Webster] Turn it up!
能量 要更多能量
Power! More power!
Whoa!
Ow!
7.75 流量7点75
75… Seventy-five. Current
这里有七级的电流 但是不是在这里 所以就…
There's a current Ieve of 7 that is not supposed to be on bar...
在这里
Oh, here it is!
[COMPUTER POWERS DOWN]
发生了什么事?
[Webster] What's going on?
我不知道 没有电了
I don't know. The power's gone.
一定是格斯关掉的
Gus must have puIIed the pIug out.
成功了 真的成功了
It worked.
我成功了…我…
It worked! I got t!
你做了什么?
[Webster] What have you got?
- 把螺丝给我 - 这个螺丝?
- Give me that screw. - This screw?
- 那个螺丝 - 绝不
- That screw. - Never!
嘿 等等 我看不见了
[Webster] Hey, wait. I can't see.
[WEBSTER GRUNTS]
什么?
[Vera] What?
天啊…
HoIy...!
不…阻止它
[Lorelei] No! Make it stop!
我没办法 它失去控制了
I can't ! t's out of controI!
但是怎么会呢? 哪里来的能量?
But how? Where's it getting the power from?
它自己弄的
It's feeding itseIf.
它要活下去
It wants to Iive!
[CAR HORNS HONK AND PEOPLE SCREAM]
就是这里 我们去动物园
It's this thing here. We'lI go to the zoo.
我们明天去 然后再去别的…
I'II do that tomorrow, and then we'lI go on to the...
- 发生什么事?我怕 - 没关系 瑞奇
- What's happening? - It's okay, Ricky.
把灯打开
Put the Iights on!
住手 你会杀了他
Stop t! You're kiIIing him!
住手
Stop it!
放我下来
Hey. Put me down!
别把我们留在这里 超人
Don't Ieave us a one in here! Superman!
我懂了
Oh, I get it.
能源轴是能源出处 对
The coaxiaI energy shaft is engaging the grid source factor. Right.
我们完了 我要先溜了
We're through, frogface. I'm spIitt ng.
嘿 等一下
Hey, wa t a minute!
女孩 快离开那里
GirIs. GirIs, come out of there!
救我 拜托
HeIp me! PIease!
老妹?
Sis?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
那是什么?
What is that?
[SCREAMS]
罗蕾莱
Lore ei!
老妹 我是你哥 不要…
Sis, t's your Bubba!
（危险程度 零）
救我
HeIp me. HeIp!
超人
Superman!
甜心
Honey!
甜心 我卡在这里 救命  那我呢?
Honey, 'm stuck here! HeIp! What about me?
小心
Look out!
[SCREAMS THEN GRUNTS]
老哥?
Bubba?
谢谢 兄弟
Thank you, brother.
普通还是高级的?
ReguIar or premium?
管他的 她好久没有加油了 给她最好的
She hasn't had a drink n so ong, give her a tankfuI of the good stuff.
你觉得如何 格斯?
How you doing?
请不要跟我说话 我的麻烦已经够多了
P ease don't taIk to me. I'm having enough troubIe hang ng on.
好 我们可以慢一点 你非常安全
Okay, we'lI go sIow. You're perfectIy safe.
我不会跟你争辩这点
I'm not gonna argue w th you.
能够破解我的机器 就能做到任何事情
I mean, any man who can trick my machine can do anything.
你是如何破解防御的?
How did you beat my defenses?
那个机器是很厉害 但它不知道会有麻烦
Those defenses are good as Iong as t didn't know it's n troubIe.
这一次它不知道危险的地方 我只是把特殊化学物拿来
This t me it didn't see the danger. I went in with pIa n oId acid.
当那种酸到达一定温度时 它就会毁掉所有的东西
It didn't know that when acid gets hot, it' eat through anything.
小心树
- Watch the trees. - Whoa!
我想这次它死于酸性消化不良
I guess it died of acid indigestion.
那我的老板 和两位小姐会如何?
But what's gonna happen to Ross and the Iadies?
他们要去和警察谈谈了 那不是你的问题了
They're gonna have to see the poIice. It's not your probIem anymore.
我们到大都会了吗?
Are we in MetropoIis yet?
还没 我们要在那里停一下
Nope. We're just gonna make a Iitt e stop right over there.
Whoa!
我们降落了 格斯
We're on the ground, Gus. Morning.
- 你没事吧 超人? - 我没事
- You okay, Supe? - I'm fine.
对不起
Excuse me a second.
你们可以给我一些这个吗?
Can you guys spare one of these?
- 当然可以 超人 - 这是超人 是吧?
- Sure, Superman. - It s Superman, isn't it?
你在闲玩笑吗?
Are you kidding? Is that...?
没看到我们在天上飞吗?
Didn't you see us f y out of the sky?
只有我和超人会飞耶 这位是超人吗?
We're the onIy two men who can fIy. "Is it Superman?"
这就对了
SUPERMAN: Just right.
好 格斯 走吧
Okay, Gus, Iet's go.
我就怕你这样说 我想我还是坐公车好了
I was afraid you'd say that. I thought I'd take the bus.
随便你啦 你们老板有电脑吗?
WeII, suit yourse f. Does your boss have a computer here?
是 他有一台小电脑
Yeah, he got a IittIe bitty one about that big.
你告诉他 格斯会做很多电脑相关事情
You te I him he can do a ot worse than to give Gus Gorman here a job.
谢谢你 超人
Wow, thank you, Supe.
保重了
Take care.
我们再会了
I'II see you around.
再见
SUPERMAN: So Iong.
保重 老兄
Take t easy, man.
有人强力谁荐你 你想要这份工作吗?
WeII, you got good references, so if you want that job....
不要了 这不适合我 我想我要去搭公车
Nah, this is not for me. I think I'lI take that bus.
能告诉我车站在哪里吗?
Can you te me where the bus station is?
是的 到那里要走9或10英里路
Yeah, about n ne, 10 miIes over there.
9或10英里路 好吧
Nine or 10 miIes. Okay.
你真的跟他一起飞吗?
Hey. You reaIIy fIew with him?
超人? 你们以前见过超人吗?
Superman? Have you ever seen Superman before?
没有
No.
你不知道我和他的关系? 我和超人?
Oh, you don't know about me and h m? Me and Superman?
是 我们都是一起的
Yeah, we go way back together.
我们一直 通常 有时候是…
We aIways, usuaIIy, sometimes, we....
9或10英里路吗?
Nine or 10 miIes?
我想我用走的
I think I'II waIk.
对 我用走的
Yeah, I' waIk.
对
Yeah.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
克拉克
CIark.
真是惊讶 请进
What a nice surprse! Come n.
- 嗨 肯特先生  - 嗨 瑞奇
- Gosh. Hi, Mr. Kent. - Hi, Ricky.
- 猜猜看今晚谁要来吃饭? - 是谁?
- Guess who Mom's hav ng d nner with. - Who?
超人
Superman!
对了 这就是我要来告诉你的事
Yeah, that's what I came to teII you.
超人要告诉你 他真的很抱歉
Superman said to teII you he's sorry...
但是他有些事情 他今晚无法与你吃饭了
...but he's run into a probIem and he won't be ab e to have dinner with you.
- 我猜他错过了很多次的晚餮 - 是啊
- I guess he misses a Iot of d nners. - Yeah.
你介意我和你吃吗?
WouId you mind settI ng for me?
怎么会?
Any day.
- 我去拿东西 - 好
- I'II get my things. - Okay.
拉娜 我那天和超人聊天
You know, Lana, I was ta king to Superman the other day.
你知道 他和我 我们聊了很多
You know, he and I, we taIk a Iot.
他很难过 你当了你的钻石戒指
And he feIt badIy about you having to pawn your diamond ring.
他发现这个…
WeII, he found....
他在地上发现这个
He found this one just Iy ng around.
他要你收下
He wanted you to have this.
超人送的戒指
Wow, a r ng from Superman!
- 没关系 我来处理 - 抱歉
- It's okay. I got it. - Sorry.
你看
Look at that.
- 克拉克 - 没关系
LANA: Oh, CIark. - It's okay.
大小刚好
It fits.
真好看
It Iooks reaIIy pretty.
谢谢
Thank you.
BRAD: WeII....
- 布莱德 - 布莱德
- Brad. - Brad.
你这个混蛋
Son of a bitch.
肯特 我恨你
Kent, I hate you.
我一直都恨你
I've aIways hated you.
- 你知道为何吗? - 不知道
- You know why? - No.
- 因为你人很好 - 也不是真的…
- Because you're nice. - Not rea y.
好人要完蛋了
And n ce guys finish Iast.
[BRAD YELLS]
露易丝 我必须要交给你
PERRY: Lois, I've got to hand it to you.
还有谁能够将三星期的假期
Who e se couId turn a vacat on into a story...
变成揭发 加勒比海腐败内慕的报导呢?
...that'lI bIow the Iid off of corruption in the Caribbean?
当计程车司机绑架我时 我就知道不对劲了
I knew I was on to something when that taxi drver k dnapped me.
露易丝 你真棒
Lois, you're terrfic.
我必须这样 我似乎遇到竞争对手了
I have to be. Seems I've got some new compet tion.
Hmm?
你所写的同学聚会
The story that you wrote on the cIass reunion?
- 我觉得太好了 - 谢谢
- I thought it was terrfic. - Thanks.
非常吸引人 尤其是家乡女孩的那部分
And fascinating. I Iiked the part about the ttIe girI back home.
我带你去吃午饭 你把详情告诉我
I'II take you to unch and you teII me about it.
我很想要 露易丝 但是今天 我要和怀特先生的新秘书吃饭
I'd Iove to, but I'm having Iunch with Mr. White's new secretary.
- 嗨 拉娜 - 嗨 克拉克
- Hi, Lana. - Hi, Clark.
露易丝 这位是拉娜… 小镇献给大都会的最新礼物
Lana. Lois, say heIIo to Lana Lang, SmaIIv I e's newest gift to MetropoIis.
很高兴见到你 莲恩小姐 我很喜欢你的作品
I'm gIad to meet you. I Iike your wrting a Iot.
谢谢
Thank you.
我很喜欢你的钻石
I Iike your sparkIer a Iot.
我也是 当克拉克给我的时候 我也无法相信
Me too. I couIdn't beIieve it when CIark gave it to me.
- 克拉克给你的? - 是啊
- CIark gave it to you? - Yes.
怀特先生
SECRETARY: Mr. White.
怀特先生 看看我弄了什么给你
Mr. White, Iook what I've got for you.
各位 我爱死这部机器了
PeopIe, I am n Iove w th this machine!
对不起 如果你们不介意… 但是我午餮前还有事情要做
Mr. White. excuse me, but I have a coupIe of errands to run before Iunch.
- 请吧 怀特先生 - 手把在哪里?
- Go ahead, Mr. White. - Where's the handIe?
没有手把 你只要按按钮
There is no handIe. You just push the button.
[LANA SCREAMS]
[SPEAKING ITALAN]